

**** 702-767-9606 **♀** Las Vegas, NV

in tim-kelley-456112b9/ TimKel

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Javascript, Python, SQL, HTML,

FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES: React, Node, Express, Flask, Jasmine/Jest Testing TOOLS: PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, RESTful API's, Git

SUMMARY

Software Developer focused on delivering solutions that support team and business growth while enhancing the customer experience. I have 16 years of sales and leadership experience that has advanced my ability to analyze and identify the right problems to then strategize and develop solutions with a positive impact. Proficient in JavaScript and Python, seeking an entry level developer position with a company that has a great company culture. Open to remote/hybrid/onsite roles as well as relocation.

PROJECTS

BLOGSTONE

- A blog space built using React, Node/Express, SCSS and PostgreSOL database
- Full CRUD capability, external API calls and password encryption for user registration
- This project helped further my understanding of React Hooks and Node Routing

Live App - http://blogstone.surge.sh

JOBLY

Jobly is a mock job portal showcasing the following:

- · React.js front-end
- Node and Express back-end with a SQL database
- · Users are able to sign up, view companies and job postings with visibility to salary, equity and company information

Live App - http://elfin-breath.surge.sh

SPOTIT

Spotlt was developed for the skateboard community to upload and find skateparks or skate spots in the users area.

- Backend created with Python/Flask | Frontend created with CSS and Bootstrap | Database created with PostgreSQL
- GoogleMap API's used for maps and directions
- · Other technologies used; WTForms, Jinja, SQLAlchemy, Axios, BCrypt

For a quick demo- Click on Search or log in using "Test" credentials on the log in page

Live App - https://spot-it-project.herokuapp.com/

EMPLOYMENT

APPLE INC.

Manager

Las Vegas, NV Mar. 2020 to Dec. 2021

- Support and oversight of 150+ employees in all areas of business- Genius Bar | Business Team | Operations | Sales
- Curated quarterly strategy with all departments resulting in quarter after quarter top performance in multiple KPI's
- Developed and supported Genius Bar best practices resulting in Divisional Ovation Award (first time in 4 years)
- · Trained sales teams by learning new technologies and teaching how they might present to customers

ZUMIEZ INC.

District Manager

Las Vegas/NV Nov. 2006 to Feb. 2020

- Promoted to District Manager in 2014. Store Manager from 2008-2014. Assistant Manager from 2006-2008
 - Provided leadership, guidance and mentorship for 9 stores in NV/UT ranging from 100-250 employees
 - Implemented strategy as the company navigated digital sales environments, evolving from brick+mortar only
 - Created 3 year plan scaling my territory from last place(14th) in our Division to top 3 consistently in 2018/2019
 - · High level decision making impacting cultural values, team/CX experience, sales, payroll and inventory results

At a National Level:

- · Assisted with design decisions and testing UX for Zumiez Stash App and in-house scheduling software
- Collaborated on development of national company retreats for 1000+ employees
- Executed above retreats including public speaking and development of 500+ new store managers/district managers

EDUCATION

Springboard Software Engineering Certification

Springboard Academy

800+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 35 mini projects as well as portfolio projects. Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.

Javascript Algorithms and Data Structures

FreeCodeCamp Certification

Oct. 2021 to Dec. 2021

Oct. 2021 to Dec. 2021

Jan. 2022 to Mar. 2023

Responsive Web Design

FreeCodeCamp Certification